Hey, Austin. Josh Kendall with The
Athletic. How are you
>> doing? Good, Josh. Thank you.
>> I guess my first question is how uh how
much did you talk to Matt Ryan as part
of this um negotiation in terms of
coming here and how big a part of that
was him his being here in a new role?
>> Uh well, I mean, you know, per league
rules, I wasn't able to speak to Matt. I
mean, all the communication, um, if at
all would uh be through my agent, but I
mean, once the opportunity
arose, I mean, understanding, you know,
Matt's here, um, obviously getting in
the building today, being able to speak
with him, um, I mean, it just was super
simple decision. I mean, a guy who I
played for, a guy who I have a ton of
respect for, um, getting this type of
opportunity and extending it, um, to let
me be a part of the club, just a
no-brainer. Did he communicate at all to
you how much just his familiarity with
you on the field impacted the team's
will desire to have you here?
>> I'm sorry you that cut out a little bit
there. Josh,
>> did did he communicate to you when y'all
talked today? You said you talked with
him today.
>> Yeah. Now that
>> Did he communicate Did he communicate
with you like just that his familiarity
with you from y'all's playing days was
part of the reason he wanted you to be
here? Uh he didn't uh he didn't say that
in those exact words. I mean he just uh
extend the opportunity understands like
my work ethic like what I'll do and um
you know how grateful I am to be here
and ready to compete.
>> Justin Feld.
>> Hey Austin. Uh welcome back. Uh h how
are you different as a a player, as a
guy than you were the the last time
Falcons fans watched you play in
Atlanta? How am I different from 2019?
Well, I mean, I've I've grown up a lot
more. I mean, I've played a lot more
games since then. Have definitely
acrewed a lot more experience and uh
it's kind of overall understanding of
offense, understanding of situations,
just like anything else, Justin. I mean,
the more you do something, the more
familiar you are with it and allows you
to play faster.
And if I can add one more, what what
excites you about the uh the the offense
you're joining, the you know, the skill
position group, the offense as a whole.
What what what gets you excited about
the the group you'll be joining?
>> Yeah, absolutely. I mean I mean Ban
Drake are superstars. I mean, you know,
Mike super talented where he comes back
and be ready to go to a super talented,
you know, I mean, bunch of bunch of
awesome. played with Jake Matthews,
Elite, Caleb, Chris were drafted in my
last year here. I mean, both awesome
linemen and you know, obviously uh
having the opportunity to play for Kevin
in the past, understanding what
style of offense he likes to play play
and uh type personnel packages he
employs and the concepts he uses. So,
love it and very grateful for the
opportunity.
Josh, I don't know if you still had your
hand raised from before, but go ahead.
>> Yeah, I got I was just going to say
Kevin has described himself to us as a
tight end, a fishionado, you know, what
sort of how does he um how does that
come across in his coaching and his
offensive game plans?
>> Yeah, for sure. I mean, you know,
multiple tight end packages, you know,
have two or three on the field at the
same time for starters. Um, a lot of
concepts where you're not just, you
know, running away from the tight end,
but running behind the tight end. Not
just pass concepts where you're just a
decoy, but concepts where the tight
end's actually involved. Not just, you
know, a look over here type route, but
actually truly be involved. So, having
the opportunity to play for him in the
past, understanding his style, his
philosophy made it really easy decision
for me.
>> Do you have any past history with Kyle
Pittz?
Uh, talking about just hanging out,
guys. Been around. Yeah. Yeah. I mean,
I've been around Kyle. Yeah. Been around
Kyle. We've been a painted pin together.
Like hung out at tight end. We've just
hung out just like guys.
>> Good dude.
>> Do you think that your familiarity with
Kevin's offense that you'll be able to
help him a little bit? Yeah. You You'll
be able to speed up his learning process
of the system.
Uh,
well, I mean, I I'm definitely always
hoping helping out anyone in the room.
And I mean, if there are any questions,
I mean, love to help him, Charlie,
whatever questions they have. But, I
mean, also, I haven't been in Kevin's
offense for a couple years either, Josh.
I'm going to need a I'm going to need a
refresher myself before I start picking
up uh, you know, picking up the teaching
role a little bit. And I and Kevin does
a great job of articulating that to the
guys. And then our tight end coach,
unbelievable. Got the opportunity to
meet him earlier, just how passionate
and smart he is. I mean, it's going to
be a ton of fun in that room.
>> Thank you, Al.
>> Is there anything else?
>> Yeah, just one one other about Matt
Ryan. Just for you, how is it, I don't
know, weird, kind of different um seeing
Matt in this role in the suit and
president of football and how how do you
think what what lends him what what
about him lends itself to this role?
>> Yeah, for sure. I mean, um, what I think
really will allow him to succeed in this
role will be the same type of deal that
helped him succeed, you know, is being
one of the best passers in the history
of the game. Just his ability to
articulate to the people around him what
he needs and his work ethic and like
he's not going to stop till he gets
something right. And that's one thing I
know about Matt. So,
I don't see him changing what made him
such a great player and those core
philosophies that helped him to reach
such such heights. I don't see him all
of a sudden, you know, trying to do
something new as the president. So, I
think that that fire, that competition,
that attention to detail will still be
there.
>> All right.
>> Appreciate y'all. So, what what have the
last uh 48 hours uh 72 hours have been
uh like for you?
>> It's exciting.
Yeah, very exciting. Uh just cuz knowing
I'm walking into a good situation. Um
you know, uh that's really that's really
it. Just super excited. Ready to get to
work.
>> I know that uh you know Nate Ali is the
defensive line coach and you're you know
you're a linebacker, but how familiar
were you uh with him uh in Houston?
Yeah, I mean he yeah was a great coach.
He was there with coach Rob over there
uh with the Dline. So yeah, we got some
history together. I got other guys too
like DeMarco Helms. Um I got Coach Hugs
from he was coaching me when he was at
Bland. So I got a few familiar faces
around here.
>> Thanks man.
>> We can go to Josh.
>> I'm sorry Christian. I'm old. I don't
all this stuff confused. I apologize.
>> You good, man.
>> I wonder um how you have talked with the
coaching staff about what your role is
coming in here, what you envision it to
be, what you think you're going to be
doing in Atlanta,
>> whatever they need me to do. Um they
obviously I think they they said to me,
uh you know, they they like my game
style, my play style. So, um, you know,
just really looking forward to I mean, I
still got to meet with him, but see how
that plays out, what that looks like.
>> Justin Felder,
appreciate your time today. Uh, as with
everybody who went to Alabama in the
last decade or so, I know you have some
experience at Mercedes-Benz Stadium.
What are your what are your memories in
that building? you know, we got a couple
SEC championships
over there. So, you know, I'm uh a lot
of good memories. A lot of good
memories.
And one other Alabama related question,
we'll we'll see if it works out, but
there's a whole lot of reporting that a
guy you played with for I think a year
at Alabama and Tua might be joining this
free agent class as well. What What do
you remember about I believe you guys
played together your freshman year. What
do you remember about him? What's he
like just as a guy, as a player? And if
it does work out and he signs with
Atlanta, what should Falcons fans
expect?
>> I mean, I think he's a great leader, um,
great player. So, like you said, it all
works out, that'd be be great to have
them. Be great to be teammates again,
for sure.
And if I could just throw throw in one
more, we we've heard from a lot of um,
you know, Falcons players this past
year, especially about Jeff's defense,
how much they liked playing in it. I
mean, coming he was a linebacker. Um,
what have you heard about him as a
coordinator and uh and about his
defense?
>> I mean, I've looked up actually did a
lot of research on his defense. Been
watching since they were uh, you know,
he was with the Jets. Um, so and found
out, you know, they got the top five
defenses in the last three seasons,
three, four seasons. So, I'm super
excited about just figuring out how I
can plug in and, you know, contribute to
that.
Mark,
>> we can go back to you if you have
another one.
Everybody good?
>> I got one more. If you if you'll
>> go for it.
>> Christian, you coming from a place
Houston which is renowned for, you know,
one of the top two or three at least
defenses in the league currently. Sort
of a lot of teams are copying some of
the stuff y'all have been doing. Do you
expect the Jeff and this Falcon staff to
to pick your brain as well?
>> I think we're going to work really well
together. Um, like you said or I said,
you know, they had top three, top four
defenses in New York, so he already
knows what that looks like, how to
establish that, what those pieces look
like. So, and being that I was on a
defense that just had a pretty good
year, you know, I got some familiarity
with that as well. So, I'm pretty sure
it'll it'll mesh.
Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Awesome. Thanks everyone.
>> I just wanted to ask you uh you know,
how did things come together? Uh you
know, you were in New York for a bit and
uh uh what brought you to Atlanta?
>> You know, I'm I've known Craig for a
long time. Um and so I think that was
kind of how it all happened. Um my agent
got a call whenever tampering was
allowed to happen. and um it came
together pretty quick. Um I'm I'm
excited to be here. Excited to help this
team win some games and get back to the
playoffs as quick as we can.
>> Nick, can you hear me? This is uh Justin
from Fox 5. I think I might have been
causing that feedback.
>> Yep, I can hear you.
>> All right. Sorry about that. Um, well,
just what what excites you from from
what you know about this team, uh, about
the group. Um, and what was kind of the
I'm not sure if there was, you know, one
ultimate factor, familiarity like you
were just talking about that that led
you to sign here?
>> Uh, I mean, knowing Craig was big. Um,
played for him in Tennessee. I love his
energy. I love what he brings to the
special teams room. Um, and then seeing
Jake Bailey sign as well was uh was a
big factor. He held for me for four
years. And I think having a good
relationship with your holder is big.
And then just what the team's doing. Um,
you know, from top down. Uh, they've
made some changes and I think all for
the better. Um, and you know, they're
close to the playoffs last year. So, um,
I'd love to get back to back in the
playoffs personally and I'm excited to
try to do that here.
How do you describe your career? You
know, you've been you've been doing this
for a long time. How do you describe
your career and and where you're at at
this point?
>> That's a tough question. Um,
describe it with one word, long, I
guess. No. Uh, I'm just happy to be able
to keep doing it. Um, I'm excited for
what's to come. uh put a lot of hard
work and you know still training week in
week out. Um and I'm excited for what I
can do and what I can bring. Um but as
far as describe my career, I've I'll
I'll say it again. I've said it a
million times that uh the most important
kicks the next one, whether that's in
practice, training camp, games,
whatever. So I'm just trying to get get
ready for the start of the season um and
build from there. I think uh we got to
build some continuity with my operation
with uh Jake and Liam and then continue
to build that through training camp and
get ready for week one so that way we
can have a successful season.